It is said that Theater Lalalai only possesses first-rate actors.
据说拉拉莱剧院只招一流的演员
Akane Kurokawa is their young ace.
黑川茜是他们年轻的王牌
A great transformative actress.
她对角色的塑造是相当彻底的
She studies her given role and gains deep insight for it.
她研究自己的角色 并从中获得深刻的见解
And she has the innate ability to perfectly play out that part.
她有完美演绎角色的天赋
Her personality wasn't fitting for reality shows,
她的性格不适合真人秀
but as an actress, you can't describe her as anything but a genius.
但作为一名演员 你只能用天才来形容她
A-Akane?
茜？
What's wrong, Aqua?
怎么了 阿夸？
You look like you've just seen a ghost.
你一副见了鬼的样子
Nothing.
没什么
Akane, welcome back!
茜 欢迎回来！
You guys, sorry for the wait.
抱歉 让你们久等了
Seriously! We were waiting for so long!
说真的 我们等了很久
Let's all have fun like before!
我们像以前一样开心玩吧
Yeah!
好啊
We're glad you seem well, but are you okay now?
我们很高兴你身体恢复了 但你心情还好吗？
Huh? About what?
嗯？什么事？
"About what?" That's--
你还问是什么事…
Ah, since I got roasted pretty badly!
因为我被黑得很厉害吧
I did think that I screwed up, but I'm sure that's pretty common!
我确实认为我搞砸了 但我相信这是很常见的
Akane, your image kind of changed.
茜 你给人的感觉好像变了
Yuki, you don't like me this way?
夕雪 你不喜欢我这样？
Aqua, let's spend time together today.
阿夸 我们今天一起吧
Okay.
好的
She stole the spotlight in an instant.
她瞬间抢尽了风头
The cast.
演员
The staff.
工作人员
And even the cameramen.
甚至还有摄像师
Their eyes could not resist the mysterious gravity that she held.
他们的眼睛 无法抗拒她身上那种神秘的引力
The charisma that Ai had…
爱的魅力
Akane had it too.
茜也有
I heard about that video.
我听说了那个视频的事
You pulled many all-nighters to make it.
你熬了很多个通宵才做出来的
That made me happy.
这让我很高兴
Thank you, Aqua.
谢谢你 阿夸
Sure.
好的
We know that Akane's acting a bit strange, but isn't Aqua acting strange too?
我们知道茜的行为有点怪 但阿夸的行为不也很怪吗？
Hmm?
嗯？
Let's check.
我们来确认一下
Hey Aqua, will you pass me that pouch there?
阿夸 把笔袋递给我好吗？
I'm thinking right now. Get it yourself.
我在思考 你自己去拿吧
Why not? Just give it to her.
为什么拒绝？给她就行了
Okay.
好吧
Here.
给
See?! He only listens to Akane!
看到了吗？他只听茜的话！
So Aqua seriously likes that type.
所以阿夸非常喜欢那种类型
Akane made sure to perfect her role.
茜真是确保这个角色完美无缺
It's not like that.
不是那样的
Here, you like her?
原来 你喜欢她？
You like Akane like this?
你喜欢这样的茜？
Cut it out.
别闹了
Hmm?
嗯？
I'm telling you…
我跟你们说…
Seriously, cut it out…
说真的 别闹了
Um, your response…
你的反应…
You're serious.
你是认真的
Akane, what are you gonna do?!
茜 你要做什么？
This could seriously be serious?!
这是真的吗？
What are you gonna do?!
你要做什么？
W-What should I do?
我该怎么办？
Oh, she's back to her usual self!
她恢复了原来的样子
Wait, if he makes a serious move on you, are you gonna respond seriously?
等等 如果他对你认真 你也会对他认真吗？
Is there a chance you two might go out?
你们俩有机会约会吗？
If I had to say "yes" or "no,"
如果我必须回答的话
yes.
答案是“有”
Then you gotta make a move on him like that even off-camera!
那即使在镜头外 你也得像刚才那样 有所行动
-Seriously?!
-真的吗？
This is getting interesting!
越来越有趣了！
This is not interesting.
一点都不有趣
I'm tired of it already.
我已经厌倦了
I'm done watching this.
我看完了
First off, the concept of enjoying other people's romance
首先 在安全距离内
from a safe distance is in bad taste.
观察别人的浪漫关系 真是恶趣味
What's so great about pairing up who and who?
谁和谁配对有什么好？
What are you? A horse breeder? You want them to produce a racehorse?
你是干什么的？马匹饲养员？ 你想让他们生一匹赛马？
No way, I'm not watching it anymore.
不可能 我再也不看了
I don't even wanna see Aqua's face.
我甚至不想看到阿夸的脸
Bye-bye, sayonara!
再见 永别了
Mama…
妈妈
In my childhood, I spent several years with Ai,
童年时 我跟爱一起度过了几年
but I don't think I was able to learn anything about her in the end.
但我认为 我始终没能了解她
I couldn't understand a single thing about her.
我对她一点也不了解
How much was a lie and how much was true?
有多少是谎言？有多少是真实的？
What is Ai to me? Was I her fan? Was she my mother?
爱对我来说是什么？ 我是她的粉丝吗？她是我的母亲吗？
Or…
或者…
I thought the Yuki-Yuki pair was hot, but isn't the recent Aqua-Akane pair too?!
我还以为夕雪和信这对很火 但最近茜和阿夸这对也很火吧？
After Akane returned, she's kind of more stylish.
茜回来后变得更时尚了
She seems cute, right?
她看起来很可爱吧？
She and Aqua have kind of a bond from overcoming trouble together.
她跟阿夸因为一起克服困难 而产生了某种感情
Aqua's super conscious of her now!
阿夸现在对她超级在意的
So cute!
真可爱
It's almost the last episode…
快到最后一集了
I wish we could see more! Just when it started getting interesting!
希望有更多集 现在才开始有意思
The last season had a kissing scene at the end.
上一季结尾有接吻的场景
Right?! I can't wait!
对吧？我等不及了
Arima.
有马
Kana Arima.
有马加奈
Hey, you wanna ditch school and hang out today?
你今天想翘课出去玩吗？
Yeah.
好啊
Seriously, this can't be right!
说真的 这不可能是真的
Ditching school to hang out? We're seriously delinquents!
翘课出去玩？这可严重违法校纪
No way! This is seriously the worst!
不行 这真是最严重的
Seriously, the worst!
说真的 最严重的
If you're gonna complain, you wanna stop?
你要抱怨的话 那就别去了？
I never said that.
我没说不去
Your face told me that you had something on your mind,
你的表情告诉我你有心事
so I thought I'd be a good senpai and take care of you.
所以我想做个好学姐 照顾你
I'm such an angel, aren't I?
我就是这样的天使吧？
So, where are we going?
那么 我们要去哪里呢？
Disneyland? Tokyo Tower?
迪士尼？东京塔？
You have guts to suggest going to places like that when ditching school.
你竟敢建议翘课去那种地方
Well, if we ditch in uniforms, we'll get stared at!
我们穿着校服翘课 会被人盯着看的
But we'll lose time if we go home to change!
但如果我们回家换衣服 会浪费时间的
And there are lots of people there in uniform, so I thought it'd be perfect!
那儿有很多穿校服的人 所以我觉得这很完美
It doesn't have to be something like that.
用不着那样
Hm?
嗯？
I knew you were weird.
我就知道你是个怪咖
-Really? -Really!
-真的吗？ -真的
A young boy and girl escape from a prison called school and what do they do?
年轻男孩和女孩从一个叫学校的监狱 逃了出来 他们做什么？
Play catch at a park peacefully.
在公园里安静地玩接球游戏
You even went to buy a glove and ball.
你甚至还去买了手套和球
So weird.
太怪了
Hurry up and throw.
赶紧扔
I've never even played baseba… Oh.
我从来没打过棒球
Sorry!
对不起
Don't worry.
不用担心
Instead of a beginner like me, maybe you should've invited someone better.
或许你应该请个打得更好的人 而不是像我这样的新手
Like Ruby…
比如 露比
What kind of a big brother would let his sister ditch?
什么样的哥哥会让自己妹妹翘课？
Your sister complex is gross.
你的妹控情结真恶心
Then someone from Love For Real. You're close with them, aren't you?
那就找《现恋》里的人 你跟他们关系很好 不是吗？
Well, we're not on bad terms.
我们关系不坏
But they're still a part of work. It's not like a casual relationship.
但他们毕竟是工作伙伴 不是那种可以随便约出来的关系
Is that so.
是吗？
Most people lie or mainly act based on calculation,
大多数人撒谎或者精于算计
so there aren't many I can talk with who don't have an ulterior motive.
所以单纯跟我交心的没有几个
Whoa!
天啊
But I don't have to worry about that if I'm with you, Arima.
但跟你在一起我就不用担心 有马
Well, you should!
你应该担心
Hmm, but well,
但是
if you chose me to be that person for you, I guess it's not too bad a thing.
如果你选择跟我交心 倒不是一件太糟糕的事
Is Love For Real's filming almost finished?
《现恋》快拍完了吗？
Yeah.
是的
Is Yuki the most popular?
夕雪是最受欢迎的吗？
But Akane Kurokawa seems like she's doing good lately too.
但黑川茜最近似乎也表现得不错
In fact, who are you targeting?
事实上 你的目标是谁？
It's merely work, so I don't have something like that.
这只是工作 我没有什么目标
But you do have a type, right?
但你有自己喜欢的类型吧？
Like younger or older girls?
喜欢年上还是年下？
That's a difficult question…
这是个很难回答的问题
Recently, I often think about…
最近 我经常思考…
how the human mind is heavily affected by the body's growth.
身体的生长怎么会对人类的思想 产生那么大的影响
At the infant stage, it's hard to record memories due to infantile amnesia.
在婴儿阶段 由于婴儿健忘症 很难记住事情
The second growth spurt during puberty raised my awareness to my surroundings.
青春期的第二次生长高峰 提高了我对周围环境的认识
As I grow older,
随着年龄的增长
my mentality is what gradually conforms to my body and environment.
我的心态逐渐与我的身体 和我身处的环境相适应
The line between me and Aqua Hoshino fades more and more.
我跟星野爱久爱海之间的界限 越来越淡了
I've always been too scared to ask you.
我一直不敢问你
Do you perhaps have…
你是不是有
eighth-grader syndrome?
中二病？
You need to grow out of that. Makes me cringe just listening.
这你得快改掉 光是听着就吓人
In short, I'm saying that I'm a high schooler too.
简言之 我是说 我也是一名高中生
I find girls who are close to my age as a love interest.
和我年龄相仿的女孩 的确是我希望的恋爱对象
Though there's no mistake I like them somewhat older.
不过说我喜欢比我年纪稍大的 也没有错
So you like older girls?
所以你喜欢年上？
Really?
真的吗？
Just throw it already.
快扔吧
2ND YEAR
（高二）
Really…
什么…
Hmm…
这…
What?
什么？
It's nothing!
没什么！
Oh, that was a nice throw.
投得不错
Really?
真的吗？
Are you really a beginner?
你真是新手吗？
That's right.
没错
This is the first time with you.
跟你打是第一次
My very first.
我的第一次
Maybe I can aim to be an idol who pitches at baseball games?
也许我可以立志成为一个 在棒球比赛中投球的偶像？
I knew it.
我就知道
My feelings for Akane Kurokawa aren't romantic.
我对黑川茜的感情并不是爱情
I gotta thank Arima.
我得感谢有马
I was able to organize my thoughts.
是她让我把想法组织起来的
I was just seeing Ai Hoshino inside of Akane Kurokawa.
我看到的是星野爱 不是黑川茜
It's almost the end of the shoot, huh?
拍摄快结束了吧？
It makes me sad.
感觉有些寂寞呢
Once I put on a persona like you said, I gained popularity.
一旦我像你说的 扮演一个角色 我就获得了人气
You really helped me.
你真的帮了我大忙
Thank you.
谢谢
Your acting…
你模仿爱的演技
Or no, transformation.
或者说化身为她
It felt like a dream, like I was seeing the real thing.
感觉就像一场梦 就像我真的看到了爱一样
How do you do that?
你是怎么做到的？
Well, it's not that impressive.
我也没那么厉害
But I do read books on psychological profiling.
但我确实会看心理侧写方面的书
I just research a lot and make my own interpretations.
我只是做了很多研究 然后做出自己的解读
I add on a bunch of backstory of my own too.
我也自己加了一些背景故事
Your own backstory?
背景故事？
Yeah.
是的
For example…
例如
Ai actually had a child in secret.
爱其实暗中生了一个孩子
If that were the case, her unbroken line would be maintained.
如果是这样的话 她的故事线就没断
And it also explains many of her puzzling actions.
这也解释了她许多令人费解的行为
I'm able to understand her personality
我能理解她的性格
and calculate her thoughts like through a math formula!
像通过数学公式一样计算她的想法
How much of Ai's thinking pattern can you figure out?
你对爱的思维模式了解多少？
Umm…
这个…
Up to what kind of life she led and what kind of men she liked…
她过着什么样的生活 喜欢什么样的男人
I think I'd be able to figure most of that out.
我想我能明白大部分
Talent gathers in the entertainment world.
演艺圈真是人才济济
For me, that carefree, cluster of talent, Ai Hoshino, was a mystery.
对我来说 那个无忧无虑 才华横溢的星野爱是个谜
I could not understand what she felt and what she wanted to do.
我无法理解她的感受和她想做的事
This talent called Akane Kurokawa
这个天才叫黑川茜
can understand and trace Ai's actions much more than me,
她比我更能理解和追踪爱的行为
even though I had spent years with her.
尽管我跟爱一起过了很多年
Our relationship is simply professional.
我们的关系只是工作关系
Once this program ends, there will be no interaction between us.
一旦这个节目结束 我们之间将不会有任何互动
However,
不过…
I can use Akane Kurokawa.
我可以利用黑川茜
There's no way I can let her go right now.
我现在不可能让她走
COUPLE ESTABLISHED
（恋爱达成）
This is seriously the worst.
这是最糟糕的
Drop dead, you idiot.
去死吧 你个白痴
And that's a wrap for the shoot of We're About To Fall In Love ♥ For Real!
《现在开始认真恋爱》杀青！
Good work, everyone!
大家辛苦了！
Man, when I think back, it went by really quick.
天啊 回想起来 时间过得真快
A lot happened, but I honestly enjoyed it.
虽然发生了很多事 但我真的很开心
If you can say that, Akane, we got no complaints here!
茜 如果你能这么说 我们就没什么可抱怨的了
So…
所以…
Can we ask the good stuff?
我们能问点好事吗？
About that last kiss! Are you two really gonna go out?!
关于最后那个吻 你们俩真要去约会吗？
What's gonna happen?!
会发生什么？
I don't know.
我不知道
The program's flow was to accept it back there,
按照节目的流程 我得接受这段关系
but I have work, so I can't be dating…
但我有工作 所以我不能约会
Oh, come on, even if you're a celebrity,
拜托 即使你是个名人
it's normal to have a boyfriend or two in high school!
在高中交一两个男朋友也是很正常的
Yuki, you probably have one after another, right?
夕雪 你男朋友一个接一个吧？
Is that how you see me?
你是这么看我的吗？
Seriously, I've always prioritized my work,
说真的 我一直把工作放在第一位
so I've never had a boyfriend before.
所以我从来没有交过男朋友
No way!
不可能
I hear it's true.
我听说这是真的
The girls at Yuki's school said the same thing.
和夕雪同演艺学校的女生也这么说
She's surprisingly hard to get.
她特别难追
But apparently, many models are dating.
显然很多模特都在约会
The ratio of idols or actresses dating should be similar to average people's.
偶像或女演员约会的比例 应该与普通人相似
Well, I'm sure that ratio is pretty low for people in agencies that ban dating.
我敢肯定 在禁止约会的经纪公司里 这个比例很低
Though some are caught by the press.
虽然有些被媒体发现了
In that aspect,
从这方面来说
it's good to start dating on a show because it won't become a scandal!
在节目中开始约会是件好事 因为它不会成为丑闻
But…
但是…
That's right, I want you guys to use the show to your advantage.
没错 我希望你们 能好好利用这个节目
The program won't interfere from here.
从现在开始 节目组不会干扰你们了
If you wanna go out or break up, that's up to you guys.
你们是想约会还是分手 取决于你们自己
There are a number of pairs who've even gotten married.
有很多情侣甚至结婚了
And some keep up the couple act for a few months too, just for show.
有些人还会保持情侣关系 表演几个月 为了作秀
Make sure to rack your brain
一定要考虑清楚
and make your own decision.
自己做决定
In this industry,
在这个行业里
there's a ton of bad grown-ups who'll use your talent and toss you later.
有很多坏大人会利用你们的才能 然后再扔掉你们
Many sweet temptations exist in this field,
在这个领域存在着许多甜蜜的诱惑
but the kids who tend to go with the flow all end up in a hellhole.
但那些倾向于随波逐流的孩子 最终都会陷入地狱
That's my advice to you as a bad grown-up.
这是我作为一个坏大人给你们的建议
Speaking of which, where's the bad kid?
说到这个 那个坏孩子在哪儿？
Love For Real has good reviews.
《现恋》口碑不错
I guess my decision to use you wasn't a mistake.
看来我决定用你是对的
Who knows.
谁知道呢？
As a result, it just looks like we gathered attention from the backlash.
看来我们只是 因为负面评论而吸引了注意力
I heard you made up for that with your own hands.
那段弥补视频 我听说是你亲手操办的
But that video became a bit of a problem with the higher-ups.
但视频给高层们造成了一个小问题
It's a hard-and-fast rule in this industry to never leak footage from the filming.
在这一行 绝对不能泄露 拍摄过程中的镜头是一条铁规
So they were questioning that issue.
所以他们对这一点提出了质疑
Despite being a cast member, you violated that rule.
虽然你是演员 但你违反了规定
Even the topic came up to sue Ichigo Production for damages.
甚至有人提出起诉莓制作公司 要求其赔偿损失
But that didn't happen, did it?
但这事并没发生 不是吗？
It says the cast can upload offstage shots to the official accounts in the contract.
合同里说演员可以 把幕后镜头上传到官方帐号
That's why I uploaded the video to the official social media account,
所以我把视频 上传到了官方的社交媒体帐号
so I did my work just like the contract said.
我是按照合同的要求做了我的工作
You sure know what you're doing.
你倒是门清
Thanks.
谢谢
And you carried out the deal with me and did a good job.
你完成了我的要求 而且做得很好
I'll have to compensate you properly.
我得好好补偿你
You wanna go eat some sushi sometime next week?
下周找个时间一起去吃寿司吧？
I'll let you hear my juicy story on Ai.
我会讲爱的有趣故事给你听
I'll keep it open.
随时等你
Oh, Aqua!
阿夸
Come here for a minute!
过来一下
You're not getting away!
你跑不掉的
It really was fun.
真的很好玩
Hey, Aqua…
阿夸
What do you wanna do from here?
你现在想做什么？
What do I wanna do? Ah.
我想做什么？
The episode's been released already,
这一集已经播出了
so we'll have to act like a couple for a while.
所以我们得演一段时间情侣
Well, of course I know that much.
我当然知道这些
-So then… -So that's why…
-那么… -所以你…
Um…
那个…
Is our relationship just work?
我们只是工作关系？
Or is this serious?
还是真要谈恋爱？
Well, it's not exactly work.
并不全是工作
You don't have to mind me.
你不用顾忌我的感受
Aqua, you don't see me as a love interest, right?
阿夸 我并不是你心目中的 恋爱对象吧？
Well…
那个…
I can tell that much.
我看得出来
It's true that I don't see you as a love interest.
我的确没把你当做恋人
I consider this relationship as an extension of work.
我认为这种关系是工作的延伸
However, I do have a strong interest in you as an actress, Akane.
不过 我确实 对你这个演员很感兴趣 茜
This isn't a lie.
这不是谎话
I see.
原来如此
Oh well.
也好
Since those are the words that make me the happiest to hear.
因为这些话是我最高兴听到的
Then as work, let's be boyfriend-girlfriend.
那么为了工作 我们做男女朋友吧
We'll leave it to Yuki and Nobu to be the real boyfriend-girlfriend.
真正的男女朋友 就让夕雪和信行来吧
What?
什么？
You didn't notice?
你没注意到吗？
Yuki and Nobu started going out the other day.
夕雪和信行前几天开始约会了
Seriously? But she rejected him during the shoot…
真的吗？但她在拍摄期间拒绝了他
She's very clever.
她很聪明
But I do like that about Yuki.
我喜欢夕雪这一点
Looks like this is really Yuki's first boyfriend in her life.
看来这真是夕雪的第一任男友
You can never tell.
谁也说不准
See you later!
回头见
Good night!
晚安
Mem, you aren't taking a cab?
你不打车吗？
No, since I can walk home from here.
不打 我可以从这里走回家
Oh yeah, we live pretty close.
是啊 我们住得很近
Most people in this industry live in this area anyway.
这一行大多数人都住在这个地区
I'm sad.
真难过啊
I liked this set so much.
我非常喜欢这个片场
I see.
这样啊
But Aqua, you're not that sad, are you?
但是阿夸 你没那么难过吧？
Since you're Akane's boyfriend now!
既然你现在是茜的男朋友了
Our relationship's just for work.
我们的关系只是为了工作
Well, that could be the start?
有这么个开始 不也挺好的？
I mean, you could eventually become serious.
我是说 你最终会变得认真起来的
I won't.
我不会的
That's what you say now, but you were all red when Akane was acting as Ai!
你现在是这么说 但茜扮演爱的时候 你满脸通红
Hmm?
嗯？
By the way, I'm surprised you knew. You're not in the B Komachi generation.
对了 我很惊讶你竟然知道爱 你不是B小町那一代人吧
Well, B Komachi is everyone's dream!
不对 B小町是每个人的梦想
Just between you and me,
这些话 我只跟你说
my dream was to become an idol.
我的梦想是成为偶像
But a lot happened, and I gave up.
但是发生了很多事情 我放弃了
And now I'm happily a YouTuber!
我很高兴我现在是油管博主
Hm.
嗯
Then why don't you join us?
那你为什么不加入我们呢？
Oh. What?
什么？
The newly formed B Komachi is currently hiring members.
新一代B小町目前正在招募成员
Me in B Komachi?
我去B小町？
You're joking…
你开玩笑吧
Subtitle translation by: Kanami Kitabayashi
字幕翻译：宋宛娇